Guide to the Vern Haugland Papers 1908-1987
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Vern Haugland Papers
1908-1987
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 153
Haugland, Vern, 1908-1984
11.75 linear feet and 1 oversized box
Vern Haugland was a journalist who served in World War II and covered flight and space exploration. The collection contains a variety of materials collected and produced by Haugland as part of his journalism career, personal writing, and enduring interest in the military.
Biographical Note
Vern Haugland was born May 27, 1908, to Olaus and Hannah Haugland of Litchfield, Minnesota, the eighth of eleven children. In 1913, the family moved to a ranch in Meagher County, Montana. After graduating from Gallatin High School, Haugland attended the University of Washington for two years, and finished his degree at the State University of Montana in Missoula in 1931, receiving his BA in Journalism. He then worked for two years with the Missoula Sentinel and the Daily Missoulian. In 1933, he moved to Butte, Montana, and worked as a general reporter for The Montana Standard, and in 1936 Haugland joined the Associated Press' Salt Lake City Bureau. Two years later he transferred to the Los Angeles Bureau. While there he was given the assignment of dating the ten most eligible ladies of Hollywood.
When the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor on December 7, 1941, Haugland volunteered for overseas duty. He was the first AP reporter to arrive in Brisbane, Australia. On August 7, 1942 the B26 bomber, the Martin Marauder, that Haugland was traveling in ran out of fuel, forcing him and the crew to bail out over New Guinea. Haugland was lost in the New Guinea jungle for 47 days. He wrote a book, Letter From New Guinea, about his experiences in 1943. In recognition for his heroism, General MacArthur pinned a Silver Star on Haugland on October 1, while he was still delirious from starvation and exhaustion. Haugland was the first civilian to receive the Silver Star. After recovering, he continued to cover the war in the Pacific. He returned to the United States in mid-1944 for a short stay, during which he married his long-time sweetheart, Tesson McMahon. He and Tess had two daughters, Taya and Marcia. Towards the end of the war, Haugland became an Air Correspondent with the Associated Press. This special group of correspondents were the first to arrive in Shanghai and visit Hiroshima and Nagasaki after the dropping of the atomic bombs. At the end of the war, he was assigned to cover the Indonesian Revolution.
He was forced to return to the United States in March of 1946 after contracting jaundice. Haugland was assigned to the AP's Washington Bureau and in 1951 took over as aviation editor. Starting in the 1950s until his retirement, he covered the NASA space program. NASA called him "the world's most experienced splashdown reporter." Haugland retired from the AP in 1973 and moved with his wife Tess to San Clemente, California. Haugland never retired from writing, though. He wrote two books on the Eagle Squadrons, a group of American men during World War II who flew for the British before America entered the war. He was finishing the third book when he died on September 15, 1984. His wife finished the book for him.
The collection contains a variety of materials collected and produced by Haugland as part of his journalism career, personal writing, and enduring interest in the military. Correspondence from his career was mostly conducted for research purposes and includes exchanges with many military personnel. Writings include manuscripts of articles, including those written for the Associated Press and his novel. There are financial materials related to his many travels for his work, along with his travel documents like passports. There are research materials related to NASA and the space program, as well as K'tut Tantri in Indonesia. There are clippings of many of his articles, some personal materials, and memorabilia. Last, there are photographs of Haugland and that he collected for his work.
The collection is divided into ten series:
Series I: General Correspondence, 2.75 linear feet, 1942-1984
Series II: Writings, 3.75 linear feet, 1942-1983
Series III: Financial Records, 29 folders, 1938-1981
Series IV: Legal Documents, 12 folders, 1942-1977
Series V: Research Materials, 1.75 linear feet, 1943-1987
Series VI: Clippings, 1.25 linear feet, 1930-1986
Series VII: Personal, 1.25 linear feet, 1908-1987
Series VIII: Memorabilia, 2.0 linear feet, 1942-1978
Series IX: [empty]
Series X: Photographs, 1936-1983
Series XI: Lithographs, 1 folder, undated
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and the University of Montana--Missoula.
The materials in this collection were originally donated to The University of Montana School of Journalism in 1988. Upon receipt of the materials, the School of Journalism retained all bound books for display purposes while all other materials were immediately transferred to the K. Ross Toole Archives. In 1990 the School of Journalism transferred all bound books and subsequent materials received from the donor to the archives for final processing.
Transferred from the University of Montana School of Journalism, 1990.
The following books were moved to the Mansfield Library's general book collection during 1998 processing:
The Aerospace Corporation its Work: 1960-1980, Portz, Matthew H.
All About Helicopters, Howard, Jean Ross
Always Another Dawn: The Story of a Rocket Test Pilot, Crossfield, A. Scott with Clay Blair, Jr.
A New Way of the Cross, Ather M. Raymond, O.C.S.O.
Apollo, Chappell, Russell
Apollo at Go, Sutton, Jeff
Apollo Expeditions to the Moon, Cortright, Edgar
Around the World in 1,000 Pictures: A Photographic Encyclopedia of Travel to Foreign Lands, Runyon, A. Milton and Bergane, Vilma F.
The Birth of Aviation: Kitty Hawk, N.C., Brown, Aycock
The Book of Mars, Glasstone, Samuel
Catcher in the Rye (A Critical Commentary), Salinger, J.D.
Celebrating the National Air and Space Museum, CBS Publications
Chariots from Apollo: A History of Manned Lunar Spacecraft, Brooks, Courtney G.; Grimwood, James M.; Swenson, Lloyd S., Jr.
Crusade for Airpower: The Story of the Air Force Association, Straubel, James H.
Discussions of the Novel, Sale, Roger
Famous First Flights Across the Atlantic, Delear, Frank J.
Flying Saucers from Outer Space, Keyhoe, Donald E.; Major U.S. Marine Corps, Retired
Footprints on the Moon, The Associated Press
For There is in London, Tour Book
From the Captain to the Colonel: An Informal History of Eastern Airplanes, Sterling, Robert J.
From the Wright Brothers to the Astronauts: The Memoirs of Major General Benjamin D. Foulois, Glines, Colonel C.V., USAF
Guam Interlude, Arnhym, Albert A.
The History of Rocket Technology, Emme, Eugene M.
History of Rocketry and Space Travel, von Braun, Wernher; Ordway III, Frederick I.
It's Really Round, Anderson, Don
Journey to Tranquility: The Long Competitive Struggle to Reach the Moon, Young, Hugo; Silcock, Bryan; Dunn, Peter
Kill Devil Hill: Discovering the Secret of the Wright Brothers, Combs, Harry with Caidin, Martin
Loud and Clear: The Full Answer to Aviation's Vital Questions: Are the Jets Really Safe?, Sterling, Robert J.
Men of the Pentagon: From Forrestral to McNamara, Borkland, C.W.
NASA Astronauts: Fact Sheet; Release Ne. 75-20, January, 1975
The Next Fifty Years of Flight, Bergaust, Erik
On the Shoulders of Titans: A History of Project Gemini, Hacker, Barton C.; Grimwood, James M.
Orders of Magnitude: A History of NACA and NASA, 1915-1976, Anderson, Frank W., Jr.
The Partnership: A History of the Apollo-Soyuz Test Project, Ezell, Edward Clinton; Ezell, Linda Neuman
The Pilot Maker, Lloyd L. Kelly as told by Robert B. Parke
The Probable Cause_The Truth about Air Travel Today, Sterling, Robert J.
Project Vanguard: The Story of Project Vanguard by its Head of Propulsion, Stehling, Kurt R.
The Putt-Putt Air Force: The Story of the Civilian Pilot Training Program and the War Training Service (1939-1944), Strickland, Patricia
Reporting to Remember: Unforgettable Stories and Pictures of World War II, Correspondents of the Associated Press
Revolt in Paradise, Tantri, K'tut
Rockets and Missiles, Bergaust, Erik
Safety in General Aviation, Hoekstra, Harold D.; Huang, Shung-chai
Seven Decades of Progress: A Heritage of Aircraft Turbine Technology, General Electric
The Sky Pirates: The Complete, Authoritative Story of Aerial Hijacking, Describing What Has Happened and Why, Arey, James A.
Spaceport U.S.A.: The Story of Cape Canaveral and the Air Force Missile Test Center, Caidn, Martin
Spinoff 1977: An Annual Report, Haggerty, James J.
Spun Sequence, Poems by John Varney
The Story of the Winged-S: Late Development and Recent Photographs of the Helicopter: An Autobiography, Sikorsky, Igor I.
Supermarine Spitfire, Bowyer, Chet
This New Ocean: A History of Project Mercury, Swenson, Lloyd S.; Grimwood, James M.; Alexander, Charles C.
TRW Space Log 1970-1971, TRW Systems Group
Two Hundred Thousand Flyers: The Story of the Civilian-AAF Pilot Training Program, Winer, Willard
UFOS-Identified, Klass, Philip J.
Underwater Man: His Evolution and Explorations, MacInnis, Joseph B., M.D.; Lindbergh, Jon M.
The Viking Mission to Mars, Marietta, Martin
War Eagles: The Story of 71 Eagle Squadron, Childers, James Saxon
Wernher von Braun, Bergaust, Erik
The Wild Blue: The Story of American Airpower, Loosbrock, John F.; Skinner, Richard M.
World Atlas, C.S. Hammond & Company
The World in 1968: History as We Lived It, The Associated Press
The World in 1969: History as We Lived It, The Associated Press
The World in 1971: History as We Lived It, The Associated Press
The World in 1972: History as We Lived It, The Associated Press
The U.S. Air Force Academy Library holds some materials related to Haugland.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Tantri, K'tut
Great Britain. Royal Air Force. Eagle Squadron; United States. Army Air Forces; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration; Associated Press; University of Montana--Missoula--Alumni and alumnae
New Guinea--Description and travel; Indonesia--History
Americans--Great Britain; Americans--New Guinea; Fighter pilots--Great Britain; Fighter pilots--United States; Outer space--Exploration; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives, American; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, American; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, British.; World War, 1939-1945--Journalists; World War, 1939-1945--New Guinea; World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Ocean
Personal papers; Photographs
Photographs; International Relations; Journalism; Military
Authors, American.; Journalists--United States; War correspondents--United States
- General Correspondence, 1942-1984; Series I; 2.75 linear feet
  The series contains correspondence that Haugland conducted with various people throughout his career with the Associated Press and into his retirement. Haugland conducted correspondence with his research subjects, including the Eagles, an American World War II flying force fighting for Britain before America entered the war, and K'tut Tantri, and Indonesian women who Haugland made the subject for one of his manuscripts. Haugland also corresponded with Great Britain's Prince Philip in his research of the Eagles, who made him an honorary member of their group. Haugland had a great deal of correspondence with book companies who wanted Haugland to write for them. He also corresponded with military personnel, many of whom were personal friends of Haugland's because of his NASA splashdown coverage for the AP.
  The series is divided in two parts. Part One: General Correspondence, is divided chronologically, and Part Two: By Subject, is divided alphabetically.
  - General Correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - General Correspondence, 1943 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - General Correspondence, 1944 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - General Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - General Correspondence, 1946 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - General Correspondence, 1947 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - General Correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - General Correspondence, 1949 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - General Correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - General Correspondence, 1951 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - General Correspondence, 1952 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - General Correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - General Correspondence, 1955 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - General Correspondence, 1956 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - General Correspondence, 1959 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - General Correspondence, 1961 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - General Correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - General Correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - General Correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - General Correspondence, 1967 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 1/29)
  - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 1/32)
  - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 1/33)
  - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 1/34)
  - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 1/35)
  - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 1/37)
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - General Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - General Correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 2/6)
  - "The AAF against Japan," dealing with, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Associated Press memos, 1954, 1958 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Associated Press memos, 1962 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Associated Press memos, 1963 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Associated Press memos, 1964 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Associated Press memos, 1965 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Associated Press memos, 1966 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Associated Press memos, 1967 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Associated Press memos, 1968 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Associated Press memos, 1969 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Associated Press memos, 1970 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Associated Press memos, 1971 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Associated Press memos, 1972 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Associated Press memos, undated (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Governor John Bonner, 1950 (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Milton Caniff, 1980 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Citizenship Status, 1940, 1980 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Concorde Piece, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Richard Davies, Buckingham Palace, 1983 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Eagles, 1974 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Eagles, 1975 (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Eagles, 1976 (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Eagles, 1977 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Eagles, 1978 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Eagles, 1979 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Eagles, 1980 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Eagles, 1981 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Eagles, 1982 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Eagles, 1983 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Eagles, 1984 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Eagles, undated (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Eagle Squadron, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower, 1956 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - French, 1949 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - French School Children, 1949 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Senator Barry Goldwater, 1982 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Hannah Haugland, 1943 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Tesson Haughland, 1945 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Tesson Haughland, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Invitations, 1946-1972 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Ernie L. Jahncke III, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Lyman Award, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - W. J. McMahon, 1945 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - M. B. Newman, 1981 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Jim Norris, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Retirement, 1973 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Norbert Slepyan, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 3/21)
  - K'Tut Tantri, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Telegrams from New Guinea, 1942 (Box-folder 3/23)
  - Telegrams, 1945 (Box-folder 3/24)
  - University of Tennessee, 1969 (Box-folder 3/25)
  - Vacation, 1973 (Box-folder 3/26)
- Writings, 1942-1983; Series II; 3.75 linear feet
  The series is divided into two subseries: Manuscripts and Datelines. The first portion is manuscripts of articles and his novel manuscripts. The second part of the series is Haugland's datelines that he wrote for the AP. Many articles that Haugland wrote dealt with the avionics industry, including airplanes, military bombers and the NASA space exploration. He also wrote many articles and two books on the experience of the Eagles during WWII. Copies of his manuscripts of Eagle Squadron and The Eagle's War are in the series. Many of his research notes are also included. Another book manuscript, Revolt in Paradise, is in the series. The datelines are mainly written about the avionics industry. Many news stories are about NASA and the different space missions, including the Apollo and Gemini flights. Other news stories on which Haugland reported were events in the Soviet Union, Vietnam, Japan, and the South Pacific.
  The series is divided into two subseries, then arranged alphabetically.
  - Subseries 1: Manuscripts
    - 43 Days, Vern Haugland's Diary, 1942 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - "About Tantri", undated (Box-folder 3/28)
    - "The Airborn Stories of Vietnam", undated (Box-folder 3/29)
    - "The Air force is the Biggest User", 1968 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - "Airline Navigator Turned Entertainer-Narrator", undated (Box-folder 3/31)
    - "Airline Planning for V/STOL", undated (Box-folder 3/32)
    - "Airliners of the '80s", 1977 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - "American Destroyer, WWII", undated (Box-folder 3/34)
    - "Apollo 13", 1970 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - "Assault by Air", 1964 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - A Vanguard of Eagles, 1977 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - "Aviation in the Navy", undated (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Aviation Speech, 1959 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - A Voice of Indonesia, undated (Box-folder 4/6)
    - "B-29s Complete Their Mission with Atomic Bombs", 1945 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - "B-47s", undated (Box-folder 4/8)
    - "How the Japs Planes got Their Yankee Names", undated (Box-folder 4/9)
    - "The Big Buy in the Sky", 1966 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - "The Borrowed War", undated (Box-folder 4/11)
    - "The Cheyenne", 1967 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - "Concorde", undated (Box-folder 4/13)
    - "The Cost of the Missile Program", 1959 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - "Crossing the Pacific", 1942 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Daring WWII, prepared for Kent Cooper, undated (Box-folder 4/16)
    - "Dear Deloris", 1943 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - "Destroy that Satellite", 1961 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - "Eagles," working copy, undated (Box-folder 4/19)
    - "Eagles at Malta", 1979 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - "The Retired Officer; The Eagle Memorial Projects", 1983 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, undated (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, parts of, undated (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, copy, undated (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, extra copy, undated (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, manuscript, undated (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I, old manuscript, undated (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book I and II, original manuscripts, undated (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book II, manuscript (not complete), undated (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Eagle Squadron, Book III, Selection and Training, working copy, undated (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Eagle Squadron, notes and draft, undated (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Eagle Squadron, old copies, undated (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Eagle Squadron, book proofs, 1979 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Eagle Squadron, summary of book, 1975 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - The Eagles' War, undated (Box-folder 7/4)
    - The Eagles' War, manuscript, undated (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Eagles' at War, manuscript, 1978 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - The Eagles' War, manuscript, 1981 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - "Early Days of the Space Age", undated (Box-folder 8/2)
    - "The FAA", 1959 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - "Fast, Low, and Deadly... Slam", 1962 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - "Fighters, Lovers, and Airplane Drivers", undated (Box-folder 8/5)
    - "Firepower Afloat", 1955 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - "Flight to Buenos Aires", undated (Box-folder 8/7)
    - "The Flying Circus", undated (Box-folder 8/8)
    - "Helicopter Airlines Optimistic Despite Loss of U.S. Subsidy", 1966 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - "Inside Story on Cape Canaveral Missile Coverage", 1958 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - "Introduction to K'Tut Tantri", undated (Box-folder 8/11)
    - "Jack Conroy's Fish Story", 1979 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - "The King Size Collier Trophy - Taste of Laguna Beach", undated (Box-folder 8/13)
    - "Greenland", undated (Box-folder 8/14)
    - "Last Splashdown for Skylab", 1974 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - "Lauren D. Lyman Award", undated (Box-folder 8/16)
    - "Letter from New Guinea," rough draft, 1942 (Box-folder 8/17)
    - "The Literature of Luck", undated (Box-folder 8/18)
    - "Manned Space Flight", 1963 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - "The Monsignor, the Nuns, and the Nuptial Mass", undated (Box-folder 8/20)
    - Morlaix, Book I, old copy, undated (Box-folder 8/21)
    - "Navy Air Power", 1970 (Box-folder 8/22)
    - "New Fighter Aircraft", 1969 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - "New Military Aircraft", 1964 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - "NORAD," (North American Air Defense Command), 1959 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - "North Atlantic Airlines Fight Bitterly for Landing Rights", 1961 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - "Nuclear Flight Nears", 1960 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - "Once They Were Eagles", 1976 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - "The Only Zero Still Flying", 1978 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - "On Trac II NAV System Unveiled", undated (Box-folder 9/7)
    - "Ordeal in the New Guinea Jungle", undated (Box-folder 9/8)
    - "Our Airlift Looks Up", 1961 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - "Our Supersonic Aircraft", 1957 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - "Out of the Never-Never Land", 1977 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - "George Peppard", 1966 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - "Pilot Puppeteer", 1975 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - "Plane Crash, North Carolina", undated (Box-folder 9/14)
    - "Quarterly Review", 1973 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - "Recovery Island", 1974 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Revolt in Paradise, draft, undated (Box-folder 9/17)
    - 71 Squadron, log notes, undated (Box-folder 9/18)
    - "The Splashdown Story", undated (Box-folder 9/19)
    - "SST", undated (Box-folder 9/20)
    - "Suntans and High Drama: Reporting the Space Age", 1966 (Box-folder 9/21)
    - "Supersonic", undated (Box-folder 9/22)
    - "Survival", 1963 (Box-folder 9/23)
    - "This We Remember; What One Wife Finds Unforgivable", 1965 (Box-folder 9/24)
    - "Transatlantic Criss-Cross, Jet Style", undated (Box-folder 9/25)
    - "20 Years Ago - USS Franklin Steamed into New York", 1965 (Box-folder 9/26)
    - "US/FRG Award to Republic puts Fairchild-Hiller in Dominant V/STOL Position", 1967 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - USAAF: Harold Strickland's Diary, part II, undated (Box-folder 9/28)
    - "The VTOL - Up and Away", 1965 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - "War Correspondent's Trip", 1945 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - "What do the Russians have in Intercontinental Airpower", 1952 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - "Wings over Vietnam", 1967 (Box-folder 10/4)